[{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option neareast in meaning to the italicized words.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The patient is suffering from&nbsp;<em>an ailment that keeps recurring<\/em><\/strong><\/p>","options":["A chronic ailment","A frequent ailment","An acute ailment","A constant ailment"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option neareast in meaning to the italicized words.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The dispute between the two countries has resulted in the&nbsp;<em>severity of&nbsp;<\/em>diplomatic relations<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Stopping","Breaking","Withdrawing","Cancelling"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option neareast in meaning to the italicized words.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The&nbsp;<em>loud noise<\/em> of the police siren woke us up<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Clamour","Ding-dong","Whistle","Wail"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that has the same consonant sounds) as the one represented by the letter(s) underlined.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Chant<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Cheat","Character","Chief","Chemistry"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that has the same consonant sounds) as the one represented by the letter(s) underlined.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Ba<u>dg<\/u>e<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Gin","Guest","Gasp","Grade"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that has the same consonant sounds as the one represented by the letter(s) underlined.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong><u>Sh<\/u>ip<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Official","Vision","Seizure","Revision"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>From the words lettered A to D, choose the word that has the same consonant sounds as the one represented by the letter(s) underlined.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Au<u>th<\/u>or<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Rather","Mother","Though","Thwart"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option OPPOSITE in meaning to the word in italics.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>My brother married a&nbsp;<em>loquacious woman<\/em><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Quiet","Busy","Talkative","Beautiful"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option opposite inmeaning to the word in italics.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The Minister has finally been dropped from the present cabinet because of his&nbsp;<em><u>ignoble<\/u><\/em> act<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Criminal","Ignorant","Honourable","Selfish"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option opposite in meaning to the word in italics.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>His cruelty to his mother <em><u>defies<\/u><\/em> logical explanation<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Demands","Offers","Projects","Precludes"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option opposite in meaning to the word in italics.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Orinya balances the pail on her head with&nbsp;<em>accustomed&nbsp;<\/em>ease.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Convincing","Surprising","Unwary","Unusual"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option opposite in meaning to the word in italics.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Most warring countries ends up in state of&nbsp;<em>satiation<\/em><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Hunger","Thrist","Danger","Famine"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option opposite meaning to the word in italics.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>My father's advice to me was quite <em><u>invaluable<\/u><\/em><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Useless","Useful","Helpful","Unsolicited"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option opposite meaning to the word in italics.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Musa hates Hadiza for her constant <em><u>bellicose<\/u> <\/em>behaviour<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Violent","Gentle","Meek","Troublesome"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option nearest meaning to the word(s) or phrase in italics.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Abdul is fond of his teacher though he sometimes makes <em><u>derogatory<\/u><\/em> remarks about him<\/strong><\/p>","options":["complimentary","disrespectful","flattering","appreciative"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the blank.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The doctor did not find it difficult to ______ the patient's ailment.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Discover","Diagonize","Divine","Diagnose"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the blank.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The new riot squad was armed to the _____<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Head","Neck","Teeth","Feet"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the blank.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The rise in worker's pay is truly a _______ booster.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Moral","Morale","Soul","Spirit"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the blank.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>For the sake of clarity, the professor was asked to ______ on the hypothesis.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Expatiate","Expand","Expantiate","Explicate"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>After each of the following sentence, a list of possible interpretation is given, choose the interpretation thay you consider most appropriate for each sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Although wrestling is popular, it is not my cup of tea. This means that wrestling<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Is a primitive game","Is not lucrative","Is rough","Does not interest me"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>After each of the following sentence, a list of possible interpretation is given, choose the interpretation thay you consider most appropriate for each sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Voke's&nbsp; mother keeps her nose to the grindstone.&nbsp; This means that Voke's mother<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Makes Voke grind things all the time","Forces her to grind stones","Keeps her hand on Voke's nose","Make Voke work all  the time"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>After each of the following sentence, a list of possible interpretation is given, choose the interpretation thay you consider most appropriate for each sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>She delivered her speech without turning a hair. This means that she delivered her speech without<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Nodding","Any emotion","Looking up","Combing her hair"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>After each of the following sentence, a list of possible interpretation is given, choose the interpretation thay you consider most appropriate for each sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Ayo goes bananas every night she comes here. This&nbsp; means that every night Ayo comes here, she<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Is cool and gentle","Breaks her fast","Prefers to be served with bananas","Is angry"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>After each of the following sentence, a list of possible interpretation is given, choose the interpretation thay you consider most appropriate for each sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Idemudia is in rude health. This means he is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["So rude and stubborn that nobody likes him","In a poor state of health","Is in a very good health","Is arrogant"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>After each of the following sentence, a list of possible interpretation is given, choose the interpretation thay you consider most appropriate for each sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Victor was advised to grasp the nettle. This means he was advised to&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Avoid wasting an opportunity","Deal with a difficult matter firmly","Listen attentively to instructions","Avoid dishonest people"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>After each of the following sentence, a list of possible interpretation is given, choose the interpretation thay you consider most appropriate for each sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>It is obvious that civil engineers are thick on the ground. This means civil engineers are ______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Scarce","Experienced","Many","Familiar with ground"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>After each of the following sentence, a list of possible interpretation is given, choose the interpretation thay you consider most appropriate for each sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The girl is in foal. This mean the girl is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Idle","Pregnant","Busy at work","Enterprising"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>After each of the following sentence, a list of possible interpretation is given, choose the interpretation thay you consider most appropriate for each sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Mr Okoh's plans are castles in the air. This means that plans are<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Abstract","Doubtful to come true","Great","To make him a pilot"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>After each of the following sentence, a list of possible interpretation is given, choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for each sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>In mathematics class, Olu always feel like a fish out of water. This&nbsp; means that in mathematics class, Olu always<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Feels uncomfortable","Feels shy","Feel unrecognized","Feels strange"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined words<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The traders&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">unwittingly<\/span> allowed themselves to be duped by fraudsters<\/strong><\/p>","options":["knowingly","inadvertently","unfortunately","intentionally"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined words.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>It was&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">an agreeable<\/span> atmosphere when the old classmates met at their reunion<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A congenial","A congenital","An attractive","A palpable"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined words.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>For the&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">Umpteenth<\/span> time, she warned her friend to stop shouting<\/strong><\/p>","options":["First of many times","Fifteenth time","Last of many times","Last time"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined words.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The new staff member turned out to an&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">od flame<\/span> of mine<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A former girl friend","An old Acquaintance","An old Classmate","A former neighbour"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined words.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>It was an awful day: All our plans&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">went haywire<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["were tied up","were disrupted","became difficult to carry out","were abandoned"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined words.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The material in the book is presented withing a&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">eclectic<\/span> framework<\/strong><\/p>","options":["a simple","a broad","a restricted","a clumsy"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined words.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Ohiokhen had a&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">brainwave<\/span> as to show how she could deal with the problem<\/strong><\/p>","options":["an imagination","a desire","a headache","an idea"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined words.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Surely, Ahmed is a&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">ball of fire<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["a quarrelsome person","a hot-head activist","a fiery speaker or writer","a very energetic person"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined words.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>This time, she will be competing with a&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">dark horse<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["a week and low spirited person","a person about whom little is known","an unpopular candidate","a person as strong as a horse"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined words.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>In answer to the question as to how life is treating him the stranger said \"<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">it never rains but it pours\"<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["the blessing of life shower on him like a heavy rain","he is contended with his improved fortunes","thing are getting decidedly worse","his financial status is deteriorating"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined words.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>After many years of struggle as a trader, he&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">struck gold<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["became quite rich","won a big contract","became a gold miner","became a goldsmith"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined words.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>One significant characteristics of the jet age is that it encourages people to&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">cut corners<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["not to face all problems","to want to become rich quickly","to want to avoid necessary hardships","do not do the proper thing at the right time"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined words.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Any student found guilty of examination malpractice should be allowed to&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">stew in his own juice<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["taste a repeat of the examination","suffer the consequences of his action","bear the brunt of the disgrace","forfeit the opportunity of further education"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined words.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The lady who won the beauty contest had a&nbsp;good <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">gait<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["stature","figure","elegance","carriage"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Complete the following sentences with the best option.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I don't want to ______ your morale before the competition begins.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Damping","Damp","Dampen","Doubt"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Complete the following sentences with the best option.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The new president_______ the co-operation of everybody.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Requested","Requested for","Request","Requests for"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Complete the following sentences with the best option.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The man will not_______ any act of indiscipline from here.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Console","Condole","Condone","Connote"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Complete the following sentences with the best option.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Unless your excuse of alibi is _______ by a witness, the judge will convict you.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Collaborated","Corrected","Correlated","Corroborated"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The woman complained to the police that she _________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Has been duped","Was been duped","Had been duped","Had being duped"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>After each of the sentence below, a list of possible interpretation of all or part of the sentence is given. Choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for each sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>They accused the government of&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">knee-jerk response<\/span> to issues that affect the masses. This means that ________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The government responded quickly to issue affecting the masses","The government did not respond to issue affecting the masses","The government responded to issues affecting the masses but without thinking properly","The government was slow in responding to issue affecting the masses"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>After each of the sentence below, a list of possible interpretation of all or part of the sentence is given. Choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for each sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The lecture had me&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">on the edge of my seat.<\/span> This means that _______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The lecture was interesting and I was fully attentive","The lecture was very boring and I felt  like leaving","The lecture raised many questions","The lecture was very critical of government"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>After each of the sentence below, a list of possible interpretation of all or part of the sentence is given. Choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for each sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>If you dad find out,&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">you will catch it.<\/span> This means that ______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["You will get a present if your dad finds out","You will be punished if your dad finds out","Your dad will be angry if he finds out","Your dad will be amused if he finds out"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">listened in<\/span> as the lecturer discussed my matter with the Dean.This means that _______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["I listened attentively to the discussion","I listened without my lecture and the Dean knowing","I listened to the discussion while sitting down","I listened to the discussion while standing"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>After each of the sentence below, a list of possible interpretations of all or part of the sentence is given. Choose the interpretation that you consider most<u> <\/u>appropriate for each sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Amanda has always been able to&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">twist her father around her little finger.<\/span> This means that ________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Amanda is always able to persuade her father","Amanda is always able  to deceive her father","Amanda is always able to fight her father","Amanda is  always arguing with her father"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>After each of the sentence below, a list of possible interpretation of all or part of the sentence is given. Choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for each sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>She&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">turned down our invitation<\/span> for the party. This&nbsp; means _______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["She accepted our invitation for the party","She rejected our invitation for the party","She quarrelled  over our invitation for the party","She appreciated our invitation for the party"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>After each of the sentence below, a list of possible interpretation of all or part of the sentence is given. Choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for each sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I am going back to office because I have&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">a lot on my plate.<\/span> This means that _______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["I have a lot of work to do in my office","I have a lot of food to eat in my office","I need to give out the food in my office so that it doesn't go bad","I have people waiting for me in my office"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>After each of the sentence below, a list of possible interpretation of all or part of the sentence is given. Choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for each sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>In spite of his mother's efforts, Osho has remained the&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">black sheep<\/span> of the family. This means that.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Osho is one  supporting the family financially","Osho is the one bringing shame to his family","Osho is the one bringing success to his family","Osho is the most humorous person in his family"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>After each of the sentence below, a list of possible interpretation of all or part of the sentence is given. Choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for each sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I was&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">taken aback<\/span> by his actions. This means that ______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["His actions impressed me","His actions got  me angry","His actions surprised me","His actions reminded me of the past"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the option that is nearest in meaning to the word or phrase underlined.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Steps are being taken to&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">ameliorate<\/span> the transport situation on campus.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["improve","worsen","repair","fix"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the option that is nearest in meaning to the word or phrase underlined.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The&nbsp; Vice-Chancellor thanked him for his&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">invaluable<\/span> contributions to the growth of the school.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["useless","very useful","unacceptable","unexpected"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the option that is nearest in meaning to the word or phrase underlined.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Her story sounded&nbsp;<u>plausible<\/u>.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["unacceptable","reasonable","incredible","unreasonable"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the option that is nearest in meaning to the word or phrase underlined.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>His message in the assembly hall was&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">unequivocal<\/span>.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["poor","stimulating","clear and without doubts","difficult to understand"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the option that is nearest in meaning to the word or phrase underlined.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>You must be <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">importunate<\/span> to get assistance from that lecturer.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["be unlucky","be very lucky","be pestering","give tribe"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the option that is nearest in meaning to the word or phrase underlined.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The use of 'book of tables' is becoming&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">obsolete<\/span> in Mathematics examinations.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["out of date","scarce","unnecessary","real"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word of group of words that is opposite in meaning to the underlined expression as it is used in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>He&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">intentionally<\/span> hid the documents from his wife<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Carelessly","Willingly","Unknowingly","Foolishly"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word of group of words that is opposite in meaning to the underlined expression as it is used in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong><span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">Natural<\/span> causes of death are easy to understand<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Supernatural","False","Artificial","Modern"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word of group of words that is opposite in meaning to the underlined expression as it is used in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>He is one of the most&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">talkative<\/span> students in his class.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Humorous","Sober","Taciturn","Aggressive"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word of group of words that is opposite in meaning to the underlined expression as it is used in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The whole of the city has become&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">waterlogged<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Dry","Sandy","Flooded","Muddy"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word of group of words that is opposite in meaning to the underlined expression as it is used in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>His comments at the event were&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">remarkable<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Critical","Useless","Noteworthy","Commendable"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>_______ ride a motorbike but he also drives a car<\/strong><\/p>","options":["He not only does","Not only does he","He only does not","Not only he does"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the following sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>In this -mail there_______ good news about your father.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Is some","Are","Is a","Are some"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes each of the following sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Don't let him bully you; you must stand up________him!<\/strong><\/p>","options":["For","Before","To","Against"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes each of the following sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>It was a long time before his surprise wore ______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Out","Off","Through","Down"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes each of the following sentences.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>In that _________ accident all passengers were injured.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ghastly","Fatal","Reckless","Dangerous"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the underlined expression as it is used in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>He has become very&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">antagonistic<\/span> of the VIce Chancellor lately<\/strong><\/p>","options":["helpful","critical","supportive","discouraging"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the underlined expression as it is used in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Member of that political party are&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">irredeemably<\/span> corrupt<\/strong><\/p>","options":["incurably","fully","partly","understandably"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the group of words that is nearest in meaning to the underlined expression as it is used in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Spain is&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">basking in&nbsp;<\/span> world cup success<\/strong><\/p>","options":["proud of","overwhelmed by","enjoying the","enriched by"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the group of words that is nearest in meaning to the underlined expression as it is used in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>He was advised to&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">swot<\/span> for the examination<\/strong><\/p>","options":["revise","study very hard","to memorize","plan"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the group of words that is nearest in meaning to the underlined expression as it is used in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I was&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">drained<\/span> by the time I got to the office<\/strong><\/p>","options":["tired","wet","angry","depressed"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the word or phrase nearest in meaning to the word(s) underlined.<\/b><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Mainasara has become a public&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">nuisance<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["assitant","problem","noise maker","dancer"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the group of words that is OPPOSITE in meaning to the underlined expression as it is used in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>He <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">substantiated<\/span> his claim to the surprise of everyone<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["could not prove","accept","reject","refuse"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the word that is OPPOSITE in meaning to the underlined word&nbsp;<\/b><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>At the sight of the food, he salivated <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">copiously<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["very little","profusely","unknowingly","regrettably"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the group of words that is OPPOSITE in meaning to the underlined expression as it is used in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Hostel rules often make students&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">restive<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["angry","calm","stay awake","frustrated"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the group of words that is OPPOSITE in meaning to the underlined expression as it is used in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I have since become&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">circumspect<\/span> of his intentions<\/strong><\/p>","options":["cautious","upset with","careless","worried about"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option which best completes&nbsp; the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I look forward to ... you when we resume next semester<\/strong><\/p>","options":["see","having seen","seen","seeing"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option which best completes the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Neither the lecturer nor the students ... to blame for the poor results <\/strong><\/p>","options":["are","were","is","have"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option which best completes the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The university set up a ... commitee to oversee the examinations<\/strong><\/p>","options":["forty-men","forty-man","forty-man's","forty-men's"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option which best completes the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>By the time I arrived the hall, the examination...<\/strong><\/p>","options":["was been written","was been wrote","was being written","was being write"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option which best completes the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Joseph ... reading medicine by early last year<\/strong><\/p>","options":["shall have begun","should have begun","will have begun","could"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option which best completes the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The plane ... at 4pm yesterday<\/strong><\/p>","options":["touched down","touched up","touched in","touched off"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option which best completes the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>It's been rough so far, ...?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["hasn't it","hadn't it","isn't it","wasn't it"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>On this issue, the University has&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">crossed the Rubicon<\/span>. This means that<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the university has reversed its earlier decison","the university is undecided","the university is unsafe","the university is not changing its decision"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Dr. Amadasun is a&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">dye in the wool<\/span> academic. This means that<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Dr Amadasun has strong opinions that will not change","Dr Amadasun is not knowledgeable as he claims","Dr Amadasun teaches well","Dr Amadasun misrepresents the academic community"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The policy of taxation has become the&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">Achilles' heel<\/span> of the state governor. This means that<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the policy of taxation is making the state governor very popular","taxation has become the policy that is making the governor unpopular","the governor is unable to decide on taxation","taxation is the strongest policy of the government"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>James and Jude are&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">hand in glove<\/span> in this association. This means that<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the two of them work closely to do illegal things","the two of them are always fighting","they have opposing views","the two of them use the same hand gloves"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>If he annoys me further, I will&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">spill the beans.<\/span> This means that<\/strong><\/p>","options":["I will fight him","I will reveal a secret that will hurt him","I will throw his beans away","I will criticize him harshly"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>After the activities of the day I was completely&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">burnt out.<\/span> This means that<\/strong><\/p>","options":["I was extremely tired at the end of the day","I was very sad at the end of the day","I was very excited at the end of the day","I was very angry at the end of the day"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The police have&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">closed in<\/span> on the armed robbers. This means that<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the police have arrested the armed robbers","the police have killed the robbers","the police are in the process of arresting the robbers","the police have become friends of the robbers"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>After the release of the examination results, Halima&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">cooled off<\/span>. This means that<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Halima fainted","Halima became less anxious","Halima began to enjoy herself","Halima went to a swimming pool for a bath"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word or group of words opposite in meaning to the underlined word(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>While Damisa <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">denounced<\/span> the principal's approach to the issue of discipline in the school. Osagie ________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Renounced","Lauded","Condemned","Refused"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word or group of words opposite in meaning to the underlined word(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The woman <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">croons<\/span> the word of her prayer every morning but her husband ______ his.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Murmurs","Prattles","Shouts","Counts"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">Choose the option nearest in meaning to the word(s) or phrase in italics.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Are you sure the boy is <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\"><i>indisposed<\/i><\/span> now?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Irrational","Erratic","Disposed","Unhealthy"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">Choose the option nearest in meaning to the word(s) or phrase in italics.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The clergy doesn't pay much attention to <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\"><i>terrestrial<\/i><\/span> phenomena.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Celestial","Wordly","Transparent","Especial"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">Choose the option nearest in meaning to the word(s) or phrase in italics.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Moses was a master of the game, his most victorious battles were carefully <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\"><i>planned<\/i><\/span> days before they took place.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Arranged","Mapped","Schemed","Worked out"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">Choose the option nearest in meaning to the word(s) or phrase in italics.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>One of the most <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\"><i>enormous<\/i><\/span> of all monsters is the dinosaur.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Little","Small","Tiny","Huge"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the interpretation that gives the correct meaning of the idiom in the sentence or phrase.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>In order to meet up with the deadline, the labourer decided \"to fire on all cylinders\". This means<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Shot at all the available cylinders","Threw all the cylinders into fire","Got  fed up with the task","Used all his energy to do the job"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the interpretation that gives the correct meaning of the idiom in the sentence or phrase.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>When Mary was asked to state her case, she began to beat about the bush. This means that Mary&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Stated her case vividly","Went through a bushy part","Felt ashamed to say anything","Failed to deal with real issue"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the interpretation that gives the correct meaning of the idiom in the sentence or phrase.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Since Madam Abeki's promotion, she queens it over everyone else in the office. This means that Madam Abeki______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Behaves in a superior way towards others","Is like a queen","Currently looks very pretty","No longer performs her official duties"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Suzan was given _______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A piece of long yellow and blue spotted napkin","A long napkin piece of yellow and blue spotted","A long piece of yellow and blue spotted napkin","A yellow and blue spotted long piece of cloth"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>That woman's ______ is always beating her<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Brute of a husband","Husband's brute","Brute's husband","Husband brute"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The manager could not attend the meeting so he asked Mr. Obi to ______ for him<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Stand in","Stand out","Stand down","Stand up"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Ada was unable to finish her assignment the previous day. So she gave _____ trying<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Up","Down","Out","In"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Because Onome's dress was too long, the dressmaker said that she would ________ the hem of few inches&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Take off","Take up","Take down","Take out"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The team were so active in the first few minutes into the game that they were ______ before the end of the first half<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Played on","Played off","Played out","Played up"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Aud called_______ his uncle, but he had already left<\/strong><\/p>","options":["In","On","For","Off"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I saw a N20 note ______ at my feet<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Laying","Lying","Laid","Lain"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Trial and error ______ in success.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Resulting","Result","Resulted","Results"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The boy as well as his sister ________ going<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Are","Were","Is","Was"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Everybody at home_______ staying out at night<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Enjoys","Enjoyed","Enjoy","Enjoying"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose from the options the correct reported version of the direct speech.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Emeka said, \"I do not understand this rule\" can be reported as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Emeka said, I don't understand this rule","Emeka told me, I do not understand this rule","Emeka said that he did not understand that rule","Emeka said that he did not know that rule"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose from the options the correct reported version of the direct speech.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>\"I will dance tomorrow\" can be reported as.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["He said that he would dance the next day","He says he would dance tomorrow","He said that he would dance tomorrow","He would dance the day after today"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose from the options the correct reported version of the direct speech.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Rachael said to her mother \"You are not in the mood today\" can be reported as follows<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Rachael told her mother that the latter was not in the mood that day","Rachael told her mother that she was not in the mood today","She told her mother that she was not in the mood","She said to her mother, you are not in the mood today"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose from the options the correct reported version of the direct speech.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Sam exclaimed, \"goodness gracious! I don't believe it\". The reported version is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Sam said good gracious, he does not believe it","Sam exclaimed in surprise that he did not believe it","Sam said that he is shocked that I did not believe it","Sam was shocked that he did not believe me"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose from the options the correct reported version of the direct speech.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>John said, \"when did you return?\" can be reported as&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["John asked me, when I returned","John asked me when I had returned","John asked, when will you return","John said, when would you return"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word that is OPPOSITE in meaning to the underlined word<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>What is required in Nigeria today is not&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">extravagance<\/span> but ...<\/strong><\/p>","options":["arrogance","brillance","intravagence","frugality"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word that is OPPOSITE in meaning to the underlined word<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The Speaker of the State House of Assembly was&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">impeached<\/span> last week and a new one will be ... next week<\/strong><\/p>","options":["introduced","searched","inaugurated","instructed"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the underlined word<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>There was a very <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">animated<\/span> discussion on the world economy on television yesterday<\/strong><\/p>","options":["robust","unruly","intellectual","lively"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the underlined word<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The minister's plans to improve the country's economic situation are&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">farcical<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["amusing","ridiculous","dramatic","humorous"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the underlined word<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>There was a deep ditch across the road, but after several&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">attempts<\/span>, Ada at last succeeded in crossing it<\/strong><\/p>","options":["efforts","exertions","trials","approaches"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the underlined word<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Nancy paused dramatically, but the effect of the unexpected break was&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">spoiled<\/span> by a loud snore from the class monitor<\/strong><\/p>","options":["damaged","flawed","marred","heightened"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the interpretation that gives the correct meaning of the idiom in the sentence or phrase<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The rich often give their children a&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">party of rope<\/span>. This means they give their children<\/strong><\/p>","options":["absolute freedom","much freedom","ample time","many words of advice"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the interpretation that gives the correct meaning of the idiom in the sentence or phrase<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The weak students could not&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">see the wood for the trees.<\/span> This means they<\/strong><\/p>","options":["couldn't understand the main point","couldn't find their way to a place","couldn't easily choose their future careers","couldn't differentiate trees"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the interpretation that gives the correct meaning of the idiom in the sentence or phrase<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">game is not worth the candle:<\/span> observed Thomas. This means that&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the game is better played under the bright light","the trouble of the game is greater than the reward of it","the game is meant for adults","the game is for the idiots to play"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>We had to do ... to reach Abuja<\/strong><\/p>","options":["five at least more miles","at least five more miles","five miles at least more","more miles at least five"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Because of the extreme cold this year, ... will die than last year<\/strong><\/p>","options":["many old people","many more old people","much more old people","few old people"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Please show me ...<\/strong><\/p>","options":["your red old leather photo album","your old red leather photo album","your leather old red photo album","your photo old red leather album"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>If I worked hard, I ... passed the exam<\/strong><\/p>","options":["should have","will have","shall","would have"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I wish I could stay longer, but I . . . . . . . . home early<\/strong><\/p>","options":["must have gone","have to be","will be going","must to go"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>John is very particular about his meal times. He ... breakfast regularly at eight am for the past 10 years<\/strong><\/p>","options":["has been having","is having","had","was having"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>When the sun had set ... the day had begun to get cool, we moved one<\/strong><\/p>","options":["so","and","but","yet"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the EMPHATIC STRESS written in capital letter to which the given sentence is an appropraite answer<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Tomi loves DODO for dinner<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Does Aunty love dodo for lunch","Does Tomi love fried rice for dinner?","Does Tomi love dodo for lunch?","Does Tomi have dodo for dinner?"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the EMPHATIC STRESS written in capital letter to which the given sentence is an appropraite answer<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Adamu RARELY visits his old friends<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Who rarely visits his old friends?","Does Adamu often visit his old friends?","Does Adamu rarely visit his old friends?","Does Musa rarely visit his old friends?"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the EMPHATIC STRESS written in capital letter to which the given sentence is an appropraite answer<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>John BOUGHT the book yesterday<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Did John win the book yesterday?","When did John buy the book?","Who bought the book yesterday","Has John received the book he bought yesterday?"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the options best explains the meaning expressed in this sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Mr. Ajayi is at the bottom of the move to impeach the Chairman<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Mr. Ajayi opposes the move","Mr. Ajayi is a victim of the move","Mr. Ajayi originated the move","Mr. Ajayi was put under the move"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the options best explains the meaning expressed in the following sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The sales boys traded on their foster kindness<\/strong><\/p>","options":["they traded with him because he was kind","they traded with his money because he was kind","because he was kind, they traded with others","they took advantage of his kindness"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the options best explains the meaning expressed in this sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Jide is something else! He can sell snow to the Eskimos<\/strong><\/p>","options":["he is very good at selling","Jide is trickish","Jide sells snow","Jide is very wise"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the options best explains the meaning expressed in this sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>'The problem of HIV should not be handled with kid's gloves'. This means that<\/strong><\/p>","options":["it should be taken lightly","kids should not handle the problem","it should as a matter of importance be taken seriously","it should not be taken seriously"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the options best explains the meaning expressed in this sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The head of department uses Mr. Obi as his man Friday<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Mr. Obi is used as a scape goat","Mr. Obi represents him on Fridays","Mr. Obi slaves for the head of department","Mr. Obi behaves like a man on Friday"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word or group of word that is opposite meaning to the underlined expression as it is used in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>While he is a <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\"><i>staunch<\/i><\/span> supporter of the president, she is a _____ member of the president's cabinet<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Disloyal","Faithful","Vocal","Courageous"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word or group of word that is opposite meaning to the underlined expression as it is used in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>While the girl is <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\"><i>bereft<\/i><\/span> of ideas, the boy is _____ of ideas<\/strong><\/p>","options":["In need","Bereaved","Bankrupt","Full"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word or group of word that is opposite meaning to the underlined expression as it is used in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The woman was full of <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">admiration<\/span> for her husband but he treated her with ______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Disdain","Love","Disgrace","Admonition"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Without _______ I will not accept the admission.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Accommodation","Accomodation","Accommodasion","Acommodation"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Bode and Seyi are very selfish, they care only about ______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Each other","One another","Themselves","Them"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The threat that he would be expelled from school if he failed his examination again _____ him into<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Coaxed","Lured","Incesed","Jolted"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>It is really a _____ the more you look, the less you see.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Metaphor","Hyperbole","Paradox","Miracle"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word which best completes the following sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Bunmi should not have taken offence at Emeka's ______ comments.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Innocuos","Ludicrous","Ridiculous","Notorious"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I'd give up smoking, if I_____ you.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Am","Were","Was","Are"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I heard the news _______ the radio<\/strong><\/p>","options":["From","By","On","Through"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>After each of the sentences below, a list of possible interpretations of all or part of the sentence is given. Choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for each sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>No one understands better than a man who participates in a project that the <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">proof of the pudding is in the eating<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["To enjoy the taste of the pudding","Only the man with actual experience of a thing understands what it entails","People who have never eaten a pudding cannot say how it tastes","Reliance on one's efforts is the surest way to achieve anything"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>After each of the sentences below, a list of possible interpretations of all or part of the sentence is given. Choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for each sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>When a brother has spoken the bitter truth to another, the latter often <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">wears a long face<\/span>&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Looks serious or dismal","Wears a grotesque mask","Decided to keep away from his  presence","Quarrels with him"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>After each of the sentences below, a list of possible interpretations of all or part of the sentence is given. Choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for each sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>If you don't know him well enough, you would think he couldn't say <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">'boo' to a goose<\/span>&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A would run away whenever he said 'boo' to a goose","Was very timid","Didn't know how to say boo to a goose","Was too good to drive away a goose"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>After each of the sentences below, a list of possible interpretations of all or part of the sentence is given. Choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for each sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The business man near our house is so resourceful that <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">all his&nbsp; grain to his mill<\/span>&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Everybody who comes to his mill is disappointed","He wastes everything","Everything that comes his mill is lost","He utilizes everything to bring profit"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>After each of the sentences below, a list of possible interpretations of all or part of the sentence is given. Choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for each sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The famous dancer <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">brought down the house<\/span> by her exquisite performance<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Cause the building to fall","Brought the spectators to the ground floor","Close down the dancing hall","Won great applause"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>After each of the sentences below, a list of possible interpretations of all or part of the sentence is given. Choose the interpretation that you consider most appropriate for each sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The Lincoln used to be an object of ridicule to his friends, buy they soon realized that he was a <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">rough diamond<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["A person as rough as unrefined diamond","A rough but wealthy man","A man of great worth though of unattractive exterior","A person with rough diamond in him"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">Choose the option nearest in meaning to the word(s) or phrase in italics.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>While we were waiting for the examination results to be posted, I suffered a lot from the <u><i>suspense<\/i><\/u>.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Fear","Doubt","Uncertainty","Delay"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word which best completes each of the following sentences&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>From the ... of the Nigerian Civil War, every Nigerian lost hope of the existence of one corporate Nigeria<\/strong><\/p>","options":["beginning","entrance","outset","onset"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word which best completes each of the following sentences&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Miscreants ... on stealing for a living .<\/strong><\/p>","options":["specialize","depend","participate","delight"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word which best completes each of the following sentences&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>My uncle will visit me ... Christmas<\/strong><\/p>","options":["on","by","for","at"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word which best completes each of the following sentences&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The researcher who isolated himself in a desert island was able to survive because he was very ...<\/strong><\/p>","options":["creative","resourceful","determined","flexible"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word which best completes the&nbsp; sentence&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>All the windows of the school were ... by the explosion.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["broken","dislodged","shattered","demolished"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word which best completes this sentence&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The coach about ... you complained has left the stadium earlier<\/strong><\/p>","options":["who","which","him","whom"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word which best completes the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The only student who failed the test ... away without the knowledge of the teacher.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["slank","slunk","slinked","slink"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the interpretation that you consider most appropraite for the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Whenever he discussed modern philosophy with them he did so&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">with his tongue in his cheek.<\/span> This means that he<\/strong><\/p>","options":["spoke in a funny way","did not express his true feelings","spoke in such a way that nobody could understand","spoke in  a pompous way"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the interpretation that you consider most appropraite for this sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The doctor asked whether the patient&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">had turned the corner<\/span> in other words, he wanted to know if the patient<\/strong><\/p>","options":["had started to get better","had died eventually","had been removed to another bed","had gone to sleep"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the interpretation that you consider most appropraite for this sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Macedo is a&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">bull in a China shop.<\/span> This means he is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["a very careful person","a very powerful person","a very greedy person","a very careful person but rough and clumsy"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the interpretation that you consider most appropraite for this sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>David&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">has his eye to the main change<\/span>. This means he<\/strong><\/p>","options":["keeps looking for an advantage to make money","keeps thinking about a life-long profession","keeps looking forward to seeing the day will go into married life","expects as a change of government"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the interpretation that you consider most appropraite for this sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>To&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">give somebody the birds<\/span> is to&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["help the person","scorn the person","attract the person","criticize the person"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the interpretation that you consider most appropraite for this sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Tendo&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">wiped the floor with Abass<\/span> recently. This means Tendo<\/strong><\/p>","options":["joined hands with Abass to tidy the room recently","disgraced Abass recently","was victorious over Abass in a contest recently","wrestled with Abass recently"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the underlined expression as it is used in the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Hermits are not interested in <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">secular<\/span> affairs<\/strong><\/p>","options":["dangerous","sinless","worldly","difficult"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the underlined expression as it is used in the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Mr. Adu was&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">mortally wounded<\/span> in the accident<\/strong><\/p>","options":["badly","fatally","adversely","slightly"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the underlined expression as it is used in the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The evidence of the witness&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">corroborated<\/span> that of the accused<\/strong><\/p>","options":["contradicted","prosecuted","sentenced","confirmed"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the underlined expression as it is used in the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The young woman had a&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">benign<\/span> growth in her ear<\/strong><\/p>","options":["harmless","dangerous","large","smelly"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the underlined expression as it is used in the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>At the&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">zenith<\/span> of one's chosen career, one is bound to enjoy<\/strong><\/p>","options":["meeting","nadir","conference","apex"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word that is nearest in meaning to the underlined expression as it is used in the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Uncle Hugo is really a&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">skinflint<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["a dubious person","an ugly person","a niggardly person","a slim person"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word that is OPPOSITE in meaning to the underlined expression as it is used in the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>This expired drug will not <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">assuage<\/span> your feverish condition, it will rather ... it<\/strong><\/p>","options":["ameliorate","amend","relieve","worsen"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word that is OPPOSITE in meaning to the underlined expression as it is used in the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">verbosity<\/span> of the Chairman's opening address contrast with the ... of the vote of thanks given by the Secretary<\/strong><\/p>","options":["slowness","fluency","certainly","brevity"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word that is OPPOSITE in meaning to the underlined expression as it is used in the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>You will be expected to separate the&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">tritons<\/span> from the ...<\/strong><\/p>","options":["minnows","victims","saboteurs","giants"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word that is OPPOSITE in meaning to the underlined expression as it is used in the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>One would have expected the students to take to&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">consultation<\/span> with the school authorities instead of resorting to ...<\/strong><\/p>","options":["arbitration","mediation","exultation","confrontation"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word that is OPPOSITE in meaning to the underlined expression as it is used in the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The young girl is&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">greenhorn<\/span> in behaviour but her mother is undoubtedly ...<\/strong><\/p>","options":["soft","experienced","yellow","colourful"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word that is OPPOSITE in meaning to the underlined expression as it is used in the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Nangerewa is so ... in nature that many people codemn him and praise Merenge who is&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">eclectic<\/span> in nature<\/strong><\/p>","options":["adamant","magnetic","flexible","rustic"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>After each of the sentences in questions 6 and 7, is a list of possible interpretations. Choose the interpretation most approppriate for each sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>\"The more I looked at the chart, the more puzzled I became,\" this means that the speaker<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Was not puzzled until he saw the chart","Could not understand the chart because he was puzzled","Could not understand the chart at all","Was puzzled at first, but  understood better when he studied the chart"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>In questions 8 and 9, an idiom is underlined in each of the sentence. Find under each sentence the group of words that give the nearest meaning to the idiom<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Okili was&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">the fly in the ointment<\/span><\/strong>&nbsp;<strong>of the family<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The only advantageous one","The only flying captain","The only quiet one","The only bad boy"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>In questions 8 and 9, an idiom is underlined in each of the sentence. Find under each sentence the group of words that give the nearest meaning to the idiom<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The war was long, there were reverses on both sides; at last Kikuyi gained a <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">pyrric victory<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["A victory that came suddenly","A victory won at a high cost","A victory they did not deserve","A well-deserved victory"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The wet clothes______ outside to dry<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Were hung","Were hanged","Was hung","Was hanging"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>You can have _______ of these two books<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Either","None","Any","Some"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">Choose the option nearest in meaning to the word(s) or phrase in italics.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>My attempts to see the principal were all <u><i>futile<\/i><\/u>.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["unrecognized","bad","vain","clever"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">Choose the option nearest in meaning to the word(s) or phrase in italics.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>American journalists often make <i style=\"\"><u>disparaging<\/u><\/i> remarks about Africa.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["derogatory","cut","bad","appreciative"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">Choose the option nearest in meaning to the word(s) or phrase in italics.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The loan enabled him to <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\"><i>procure<\/i><\/span> new supplies.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["purchase","give out","dispose of","solicit"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose from the option the one OPPOSITE in meaning to the word underlined in the sentence<\/b><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>We must obtain the <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">obsolete<\/span> equipment in our laboratory<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Outdated","Up-to-date","Old-fashioned","Imported"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word or group of word that is opposite meaning to the underlined expression as it is used in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Your ____ contrast with your brother's <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\"><i>frugality<\/i><\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Stupidity","Extravagance","Frivolity","Meanness"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the expression that is similar in meaning to the group of underlined words<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>He killed&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">the goose that laid the golden eggs<\/span> when he decide to spend his capital on buying a car<\/strong><\/p>","options":["sacrificed future profits to satisfy present needs","was bad-natured","became a poor person","became an important person"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>I&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">laughed up my sleeve<\/span> as he told the tales of his exploits<\/strong><\/p>","options":["was very pleased","was openly making fun of him","was secretly amused","laughed myself helpless"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word that best fits the meaning of the sentence as a whole<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>... the long run, we will make enough profit<\/strong><\/p>","options":["in","on","at","for"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word that best fits the meaning of the sentence as a whole<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The congregation ... all sorts and conditions of men<\/strong><\/p>","options":["composes","consists","comprises","conjectures"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option which is OPPOSITE in meaning to the word underlined&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>An&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">expert<\/span> will not be found wanting in this types of job but ... will<\/strong><\/p>","options":["a foreigner","a jobber","an applicant","a novice"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option which is OPPOSITE in meaning to the word underlined&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>If you are not for&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">lesbianism<\/span> it means you are for ...<\/strong><\/p>","options":["celibacy","homosexuality","nunhood","heterosexuality"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option which is nearest in meaning to the word underlined&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The effect of the new policy on the masses is rather <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">negligible<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["unimportant","useful","insignificant","negligent"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option which is nearest in meaning to the word underlined&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>When I returned to the cybercafe a week later, my ticket had become&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">invalid<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["inappropriate","crippled","discounted","out of date"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the interpretation most appropriate for each sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Had they not spoken to their uncle, they could have stayed in the room. This means&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["because they spoke to their uncle, they are now elsewhere","because they did not speak to their uncle, they are not elsewhere","even though they spoke to their uncle, they are still in the room","because they spoke to their uncle; they are still in the room"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the interpretation most appropriate for each sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>My friend gambled about all day yesterday. This means that he...<\/strong><\/p>","options":["was gambling with his money yesterday","did nothing useful yesterday","played cards for money","was jumping in the field"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose among the options, the one that has the opposite meaning to the word or group of words underlined in the sentences to fill the missing word(s).<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">diligence<\/span> of the man contrasts with the ________ of his&nbsp; wife<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Insolence","Indiscipline","Indolence","Disguise"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose among the options, the one that has the opposite meaning to the word or group of words underlined in the sentences to fill the missing word(s).<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>A <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">generous<\/span> man is not expected to marry a ___________ woman<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Garrulous","Mean","Gentle","Vociferous"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose among the options, the one that has the opposite meaning to the word or group of words underlined in the sentences to fill the missing word(s).<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>While Osawe met with ______ in the competition, Roli met with <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">fiasco<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Success","Fidelity","Disappointment","Dangerous"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose among the options, the one that has the opposite meaning to the word or group of words underlined in the sentences to fill the missing word(s).<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>This expired drug will not <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">assuage<\/span> your feverish condition, it will rather __________ it&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Amend","Worsen","Ameliorate","Relieve"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose among the options, the one that has the opposite meaning to the word or group of words underlined in the sentences to fill the missing word(s).<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The girl is <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">vivacious<\/span> today, unlike yesterday when she was ______ for the greater part of the day&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Veracious","Ferocious","Moody","Voracious"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>A list of interpretations is given below every sentence or phrase. Choose the interpretation that gives the correct meaning of the underlined idiom in the sentence or phrase.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>To <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">carry coals to Newcastle<\/span> means<\/strong><\/p>","options":["To take things to where they are in abundance already","To dirty a place known to be ever neat","To bring shame to a place and its people","To behave ungratefully to a mentor."],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>A list of interpretations is given below every sentence or phrase. Choose the interpretation that gives the correct meaning of the underlined idiom in the sentence or phrase. <\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Sarah's classmates have <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">sent her to the Coventry<\/span>.&nbsp; This means Sarah is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Well-loved by her classmates","So gullible a girl that her mates cheat her every time","Ostracized by her classmates","A brilliant representative of her class"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>A list of interpretations is given below every sentence or phrase. Choose the interpretation that gives the correct meaning of the underlined idiom in the sentence or phrase.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>My brother <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">left me in the lurch<\/span> last year. This means my brother.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Made me learn my lesson in a hard way","Did not wait for me before he took an important decision","Forsook me in time of problem","Set a trap for me"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>A list of interpretations is given below every sentence or phrase. Choose the interpretation that gives the correct meaning of the underlined idiom in the sentence or phrase.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>We advised the highly educated boy to <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">put his pride in his pocket<\/span>&nbsp;at the village meeting. This means&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["To behaves simply and ordinarily","To speak simple and understandable words","To wear  traditional dress","Not  to speak  at the meeting"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>A list of interpretations is given below every sentence or phrase. Choose the interpretation that gives the correct meaning of the underlined idiom in the sentence or phrase.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The two communities have been advised to <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">turn swords into ploughshares.<\/span> This means the communities<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Should encourage their people to plough the land","Should substitute peace for  hostilities","Should replace old equipment with modern equipment","Should invest huge money in agriculture"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Chinedu________ Chichidodo every time to face his studies squarely<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Advices","Advice","Advise","Advises"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The illness of the woman was so serious that it took a team of medical experts days&nbsp; to ___________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Pull her over","Pull her through","Push her on","Put her back"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I_________ for sure that success_________ one<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Know\/exalt","Knows\/exalt","Know\/exalts","Knows\/exalts"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>If Nerisa failed the examination, she_________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Shall repeat","Would repeated","Will repeat","Would repeat"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Let the boy ______in the way he_______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Behaves\/likes","Behave\/like","Behaves\/like","Behave\/likes"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The boy______stand akimbo before the straightened principal<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Dares on","Dare not","Is daring not","Shall not dare"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The man asked if I____my race<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Have run","Had run","Have ran","Had ran"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>You need a spiritual rebirth to be able to_______evil at all times<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ward off","Ward away","Walk out","Work on"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>After he had worked strenuosly for six hours, all Caro could do was _____<\/strong><\/p>","options":["March","Strut","Run","Trudge"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Tanuro______Boateng's feelings last night<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Hurt","Hurts","Hurted","Was hurting"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose from the option the one NEAREST in meaning to the word underlined in the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The woman takes every misfortune with&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">equanimity<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["amity","fortitude","equity","sobriety"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose from the option the one NEAREST in meaning to the word underlined in the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The man&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">deprecated<\/span> examination malpractices&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["abetted","allowed","condemned","perpetuated"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose from the option the one NEAREST in meaning to the word underlined in the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The boy really&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">irked<\/span> his father last week<\/strong><\/p>","options":["embarrassed","educated","annoyed","cheated"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose from the option the one nearest in meaning to the word underlined in the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Were their efforts in the recent time <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">feckless<\/span>?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["fecund","reckless","futile","purposeless"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose among the options the one OPPOSITE in meaning to the word underlined in the sentence to fill the missing word<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>You should know that&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">probationary<\/span> workers do not have the same sights as ... staff<\/strong><\/p>","options":["confimed","postponed","probable","proscribed"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose among the options the one OPPOSITE in meaning to the word underlined in the sentence to fill the missing word<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>From the outset, the boy was&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">arguing<\/span> while the girl was ...<\/strong><\/p>","options":["hopeful","hopeless","convinced","dubious"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose among the options the one OPPOSITE in meaning to the word underlined in the sentence to fill the missing word<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The man's&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">opulence<\/span> contrasts sharply with his friend's ...<\/strong><\/p>","options":["affluence","opportunity","poverty","experience"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose among the options the one OPPOSITE in meaning to the word underlined in the sentence to fill the missing word<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Your brother always speaks&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">euphemistic<\/span> words to address us but it is characteristic of your sister to speak ... words to us<\/strong><\/p>","options":["few","harsh","rash","polite"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose among the options the one OPPOSITE in meaning to the word underlined in the sentence to fill the missing word<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>While some activities are&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">enervating,<\/span> some of the activities are ...<\/strong><\/p>","options":["exacerbating","embarrassing","invigorating","immunizing"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes each of the following sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I believe the two antagonistic group will ... a balance very soon.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["construct","draw","strike","make"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap in the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>At the end of this year, grandmother ... with us for eight years.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["is living","shall have lived","will have lived","has lived"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap in the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The sick woman ... in bed for four months.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["lain","lay","laid","lied"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap in the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The musician really ... Europe before he returned home last week.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["explored","exploited","examined","exhibited"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap in the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I could not attend the meeting so I asked my half brother to ... for me<\/strong><\/p>","options":["stand in","stand out","stand down","stand up"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap in the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I know that James cannot find answers to the problems however hard he tried ...?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["don't he","can he","do I","can't he"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap in the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>There is no blinking the fact that my country has not fully ... its resources.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["explored","exploited","exposed","exported"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap in the sentence<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I am your friend, ...?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["aren't","don't I","aren't I","am I"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>In each of the following sentences there is one group of words underlined and one gap. From the list of words lettered A to D, choose the word or group of words that is most nearly OPPOSITE in meaning to the underlined word that will at the same time fill the gap in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Ireti was able to <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">kindle<\/span> the fire which my father had to ________ later<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Kill","Switch","Extinguish","Destroy"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>In each of the following sentences there is one group of words underlined and one gap. From the list of words lettered A to D, choose the word or group of words that is most nearly OPPOSITE in meaning to the underlined word that will at the same time fill the gap in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Josephine is <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">loquacious<\/span> while her younger sister is ________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Polite","Intelligent","Considerate","Taciturn"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>In each of the following sentences there is one group of words underlined and one gap. From the list of words lettered A to D, choose the word or group of words that is most nearly OPPOSITE in meaning to the underlined word that will at the same time fill the gap in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>In his <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">valedictory<\/span> address, the professor quoted copioulsy from his _____ lecture<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Inaugural","Academic","Original","Scholarly"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the option opposite in meaning to the word or phrase in italics.<\/b><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The chairman <i><u>vacillated<\/u><\/i> in a matter that required action.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Courageous","Decisive","Authoritative","Reflective"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>In each of the following sentences there is one group of words underlined and one gap. From the list of words lettered A to D, choose the word or group of words that is most nearly OPPOSITE in meaning to the underlined word that will at the same time fill the gap in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Although the attack of malaria was <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">sudden<\/span>, the cure was rather _________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Permanent","Extended","Delayed","Gradual"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>In each of the following sentences there is one group of words underlined and one gap. From the list of words lettered A to D, choose the word or group of words that is most nearly OPPOSITE in meaning to the underlined word that will at the same time fill the gap in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>A guest should not make <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">derogatory<\/span> but _____ remarks about the food he is served by his host<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Cheating","Complimentary","Polite","Appetizing"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>In each of the following sentences there is one group of words underlined and one gap. From the list of words lettered A to D, choose the word or group of words that is most nearly OPPOSITE in meaning to the underlined word that will at the same time fill the gap in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>It is surprising to find her <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">condoning<\/span> instead of _______ such gross misbehaviour<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Disliking","Disparaging","Blaming","Condemning"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>In each of the following sentences there is one group of words underlined and one gap. From the list of words lettered A to D, choose the word or group of words that is most nearly OPPOSITE in meaning to the underlined word that will at the same time fill the gap in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The general said that raw troops were no good to him, he needed ______ veterans<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Seasoned","Weathered","Processed","Baked"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>In each of the following sentences there is one group of words underlined and one gap. From the list of words lettered A to D, choose the word or group of words that is most nearly OPPOSITE in meaning to the underlined word that will at the same time fill the gap in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>At certain times, some <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">insane<\/span> people appear to be ______ as you or I<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Normal","Intelligent","Sober","Sensitive"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>In each of the following sentences there is one group of words underlined and one gap. From the list of words lettered A to D, choose the word or group of words that is most nearly OPPOSITE in meaning to the underlined word that will at the same time fill the gap in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The headmaster criticized John for his use of <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">coarse<\/span> language, but complimented Helen on her&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Refined","Organized","Pure","Clean"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>In each of the following sentences there is one group of words underlined and one gap. From the list of words lettered A to D, choose the word or group of words that is most nearly OPPOSITE in meaning to the underlined word that will at the same time fill the gap in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>After the long journey, we eventually escaped from the <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">turmoil<\/span> of the city into the __________ of the countryside<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Loneliness","Relief","Tranquility","Stability"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>In each of the following sentences there is one group of words underlined and one gap. From the list of words lettered A to D, choose the word or group of words that is most nearly OPPOSITE in meaning to the underlined word that will at the same time fill the gap in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>We should all have been greatly <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">fortified<\/span> by a meal, but we had only drinks which ______ us<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Poisoned","Weakened","Starved","Worried"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>In each of the following sentences there is one group of words underlined and one gap. From the list of words lettered A to D, choose the word or group of words that is most nearly OPPOSITE in meaning to the underlined word that will at the same time fill the gap in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>For a speech to have it's desired effect. It must be <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">explicit<\/span>, not _________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Vague","Flamboyant","Wordy","Difficult"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>In each of the following sentences there is one group of words underlined and one gap. From the list of words lettered A to D, choose the word or group of words that is most nearly OPPOSITE in meaning to the underlined word that will at the same time fill the gap in the sentence.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>There was <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">chaos<\/span>&nbsp; in the village and the police had to work for hours before _________could be restored&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Quiet","Law","Restraint","Order"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>In each of questions 25 and 26, choose the word that has a different stress pattern from the others<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Calendar","Blackboard","Suffer","success"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>In each of questions 25 and 26, choose the word that has a different stress pattern from the others<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Madam","Collect","Contribute","Embarrass"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>In questions 27 to 40, choose the option that is nearest in meaning to the word(s) or phrase(s) underlined<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>If experience is anything to go by, the action will prove a <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">political minefield<\/span><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["A source of political benefit","A way out of political trouble","A cause for political joy","An invitation to political problems"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the option nearest in meaning to the word(s) or phrase in italics.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>In my view, the play didn't <i><u style=\"\">come <\/u><u style=\"\">off<\/u><\/i>.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Succeed","Fail","Attract applause","Take place"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the option nearest in meaning to the word(s) or phrase in italics.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\"><strong><i>When the chips are down<\/i>,<\/strong><\/span><strong> we'll know those who have the courage to stand.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["When we get to a crisis point","In the final analysis","When the blocks are lowered","When we get to the end of the road"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the option nearest in meaning to the word(s) or phrase in italics.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>She said boxing is, in fact, her <i><u>pet <\/u><u>aversion<\/u><\/i>.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["something she likes very much","something she dislikes very much","a hobby she loves to pursue","one thing she can't miss"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the option nearest in meaning to the word(s) or phrase in italics.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The gateman does his work <u><i>perfunctorily<\/i><\/u>.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Without commitment","With speed","Grudgingly","Enthusiastically"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the options nearest in meaning to the underlined word or phrase.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Members of the panel were working at <i><u>cross <\/u><u>purposes<\/u><\/i>.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["In harmony","In disunity","For selfish purposes","For selfless purpose"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the options nearest in meaning to the underlined word or phrase.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The young man who distributed political pamphlets on campus was promptly <u><i>repudiated<\/i><\/u>.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Disowned","Arrested","Warned","Killed"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the options nearest in meaning to the underlined word or phrase.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Joseph is a <i><u>die-hard <\/u><u>criminal<\/u><\/i>.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Hard to kill","Hard to arrest","Remorseless","Relentless"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the option nearest in meaning to the word(s) or phrase in italics.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>If your life is in <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\"><i>turmoil<\/i>,<\/span> always take courage.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Deviation","Crisis","Trial","Tragedy"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the option nearest in meaning to the word(s) or phrase in italics.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Do you know one of the most <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\"><i>astounding<\/i><\/span>&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>events of my life<\/strong><strong style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Special","Amazing","Serious","Outstanding"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the option nearest in meaning to the word(s) or phrase in italics.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Adeniji is suffering from the consequences of <u><i>alienation<\/i><\/u>.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Confinement","Isolation","Enclosure","Imprisonment"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the option nearest in meaning to the word(s) or phrase in italics.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Some children <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\"><i>mimic<\/i><\/span> their teachers.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Imitate","Ridicule","Tense","Worship"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">Choose the option nearest in meaning to the word(s) or phrase in italics.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Wealthy citizens are often <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\"><i>niggardly<\/i><\/span> in their ways.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Contemptible","Beggarly","Sordid","Stingy"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">Choose the option nearest in meaning to the word(s) or phrase in italics.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I like Jude because he is very <u><i>outspoken<\/i><\/u>.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Fluent","Frank","Audible","Talkative"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Fill the gap with the option that is most NEARLY OPPOSITE to the word underlined<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Nigerian Airways is trying to improve its&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">foreign<\/span> services<\/strong><\/p>","options":["frontiers","interior","native","domestic"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Fill the gap with the option that is most NEARLY OPPOSITE to the word underlined<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The accused pleaded that the incident was&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">accidental<\/span> but prosecution claimed that it was ...<\/strong><\/p>","options":["premeditated","otherwise","treasonable","unwarranted"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Fill the gap with the option that is most NEARLY OPPOSITE to the word underlined<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Most of the electric power for the country comes from the&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">gigantic&nbsp;<\/span>dam built across the river at Bussa, several other ... ones are however, being planned for irrigaton purposes<\/strong><\/p>","options":["junior","tiny","small","insignificant"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Fill the gap with the option that is most NEARLY OPPOSITE to the word underlined<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The old prison warden has many&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">vices<\/span> and hardly any ...<\/strong><\/p>","options":["qualms","conscience","virtue","characteristics"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Fill the gap with the option that is most NEARLY OPPOSITE to the word underlined<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>It was when man stopped living a&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">nomadic<\/span> life and adopted the ... ways of the cities that civilization began to flourish<\/strong><\/p>","options":["basic","sedentary","settled","stylish"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Fill the gap with the option that is most NEARLY OPPOSITE to the word underlined<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>My uncle insisted that a pump was <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">essential<\/span> for the journey but it later proved to be ...<\/strong><\/p>","options":["invaluable","unnecessary","distorted","disappointing"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">Choose the option nearest in meaning to the word(s) or phrase in italics.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The new Inspector of Police decided that culprits&nbsp;<i><u>should be brought to <\/u><u>book<\/u><\/i>.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["should have their names recorded in a book","should be made to answer for their offence","should be booked","should be brought before him to show whether they could read or not"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">Choose the option nearest in meaning to the word(s) or phrase in italics.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The beggar's takings&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\"><i>snow-balled<\/i><\/span> every hour.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["grew","turned white","grew into a ball","turned into snow"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">Choose the option nearest in meaning to the word(s) or phrase in italics.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Once I have finished&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\"><i>all my homework, I'm permitted<\/i><\/span> to watch television.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["I can only watch television after doing my homework","I can watch television at any time","I can only finish my homework after permission to watch television","After watching television finished my homework"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">Choose the option nearest in meaning to the word(s) or phrase in italics.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>In their desire to impress their friends and relatives, many young workers <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\"><i>bite off more than they can chew<\/i>,<\/span> in terms of financial obligations.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["have more money than sense","spend too much money on food","care too much for their relatives","take on more responsibility than they can offord"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the option nearest in meaning to the word(s) or phrase in italics.<br><\/b><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The preacher has&nbsp;<i><span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">made good<\/span><\/i> his promise to visit some of his converts today.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["fulfilled","improved on","seen to","accepted"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: 700;\">Choose the option nearest in meaning to the word(s) or phrase in italics.<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The discussion became&nbsp;<u><i>animated<\/i><\/u>.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["specialized","lively","unruly","intellectual"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose<\/b><strong> the option that is nearest in meaning to the word or phrase underlined.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Look at the&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">tell-tale<\/span> signs on battering on her.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["confirming looks","suspicious marks","revealing","signifying"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that is nearest in meaning to the word or phrase underlined.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>It is claimed that the volcano near New Orleans is&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">extinct.<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["dormant","inactive","dead","disused"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that is nearest in meaning to the word or phrase underlined.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Joke has a&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">humorous<\/span> disposition.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["funny","beautiful","strong","alluring"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that is nearest in meaning to the word or phrase underlined.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>My nephew came&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">stealthily<\/span> through the back gate.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["briskly","boldly","wearily","quietly"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that is nearest in meaning to the word or phrase underlined.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The armed robbers who raided passengers on the outskirts of the city&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">came to grief<\/span> when they had a shoot-out.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["came to a bad end","became defeated","became griefed","came to a dead end"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that is nearest in meaning to the word or phrase underlined.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>\"This is a <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">miniaturized<\/span> version of your house,\" remarked the architect.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["compressed","abridged","decreased","smaller"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that is nearest in meaning to the word or phrase underlined.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Your extreme patience sometimes&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">infuriates<\/span> me.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["impresses","annoys","frustrates","amuses"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that is nearest in meaning to the word or phrase underlined.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The musician's popularity is&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">soaring.<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["changing","rising","sliding","disappearing"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/span><br><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Johnson is a stubborn man; he will never ... his words.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["chew","spit","eat","bite"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The class ... more girls than boys this session<\/strong><\/p>","options":["comprised of","comprises of","comprise","comprises"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Joseph's now a ... student but it took him years to ...<\/strong><\/p>","options":["matured\/mature","mature\/mature","mature\/matured","matured\/matured"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The rebels will soon fight back, we have been informed ... their ...<\/strong><\/p>","options":["of\/predicament","about\/indulge","on\/rearmament","as for\/advancement"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Kindly ... me your book because my friend has ... mine<\/strong><\/p>","options":["borrow\/borrowed","borrow\/lent","lend\/lent","lend\/borrowed"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Two young boys have been caught with parts of the stolen machine but ... admitted stealing it&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["neither of them has","neither of them have","none of them has","none of them have"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best fills the gap(s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The adventurers ran into many ... in the forest<\/strong><\/p>","options":["dear","dears","deers","deer"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Identify the option that has a different stress pattern from the rest<\/strong><\/p>","options":["bookcase","untie","except","adopt"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Identify the option that has a different stress pattern from the rest<\/strong><\/p>","options":["endeavour","magazine","confession","example"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"}]